<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-03T21:22:39+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Thank you and goodbye</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/30/30.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thank you and goodbye" /><published>2024-08-30T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2024-08-30T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/30/30</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/30/30.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/mindfulmonth/assets/images/30.jpg" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<h2 id="thank-you-and-goodbye">Thank you and goodbye</h2>

<p>We wanted to introduce you to habits and practices that help you live mindfully. If you’ve tried at least three - that’s good. If at least one stays with you - that’s wonderful, it means we didn’t do this in vain.</p>

<h3 id="what-to-do-with-these-practices-next">What to do with these practices next</h3>

<p>Much of the “Month of Mindfulness” can be practiced daily, and sooner or later it will become a habit and part of your life. The more you practice something, the greater effect you get. For example, the longer you practice meditation, the more calmness and mindfulness appears in each day, not just during and immediately after practice.</p>

<p>Other practices are habits that are useful to do from time to time. For example, walks, not using social media, decluttering.</p>

<p>The calendar covered various topics: mindfulness, information consumption, decluttering things and tasks, relationships with loved ones, useful habits, and so on. Now choose what you liked the most, what resonated with you the deepest. Continue doing it, think about how to integrate it into your life. Consider what habit you want to acquire after this one.</p>

<p>We wanted to show you a lot and let you try many things, so we were superficial and didn’t always explain the essence of what was happening. Actually, there’s nothing wrong with that, because practice comes first. But if you’re interested in a particular topic, you can study it and understand more deeply what’s going on.</p>

<p>This is the last letter of the month of mindfulness.</p>

<p>Thank you for being with us this month, we hope you enjoyed it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thank yourself</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/29/29.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thank yourself" /><published>2024-08-29T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2024-08-29T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/29/29</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/29/29.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/mindfulmonth/assets/images/29.jpg" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<h2 id="thank-yourself">Thank yourself</h2>

<p>The other day we wrote about activities that energize us and about dreams. It’s important not only to work and cultivate good habits, but also to love yourself. This is what the last task is dedicated to.</p>

<p>Thank yourself. For completing some tasks, or for good work, or for something else significant, or just because.</p>

<p>Perhaps there’s something you’ve wanted for a long time, or you’ve been dreaming of trying a new restaurant, or attending a performance by your favorite artist. Something you’ve wanted for a while but have been denying yourself. Reward yourself. And do this from time to time. Remember, you don’t need a reason to be kind to people. Including being kind to yourself.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Write down what you most want</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/28/28.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Write down what you most want" /><published>2024-08-28T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2024-08-28T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/28/28</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/28/28.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/mindfulmonth/assets/images/28.jpg" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<h2 id="write-down-what-you-most-want">Write down what you most want</h2>

<p>Remember what you truly want.</p>

<p>Choose a time for this practice — 10-15 minutes. When you won’t be disturbed. This time is needed for reflection.</p>

<p>What do you want? Try to answer this question specifically, rather than the question “What would be the right thing to do?”. What is it that you’ve been dreaming of for a long time but haven’t done?</p>

<p>Write down all the answers that come to your mind. Youthful dreams, current materialistic desires, and dreams of world achievements are all equally suitable. The main thing is that you really want it. If the thought of it takes your breath away, or even makes you a little scared — that’s what you need.</p>

<p>Now think about what needs to be done to make it possible. What specifically needs to be done?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Write down activities that bring joy and don’t</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/27/27.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Write down activities that bring joy and don’t" /><published>2024-08-27T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2024-08-27T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/27/27</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/27/27.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/mindfulmonth/assets/images/27.jpg" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<h2 id="write-down-activities-that-bring-joy-and-dont">Write down activities that bring joy and don’t</h2>

<p>To constantly keep up with everything and solve complex tasks, you need a lot of energy. And this is not just the energy that we replenish with sleep.</p>

<p>Some activities fill us up — after such activities, you feel joy, uplift, a surge of energy. It can be anything — time with friends or family, playing Civilization, a favorite sport, reading books about evolution or gardening.</p>

<p>And there are activities that drain energy — after them, you feel emotionally drained.</p>

<p>Take a sheet of paper and a pen. Divide the sheet into two halves: in the first, list the activities that bring joy, inspire you, and that you’re willing to do just for the sake of it. In the second — those that drain energy.</p>

<p>You don’t need to organize them or write them in order of priority. Just write down everything you remember.</p>

<p>Look at the list of unpleasant activities. Think about what needs to be done to engage in them less often or not spend so much energy on them.</p>

<p>Look at the list of pleasant activities. How often do you engage in them? What prevents you from doing them more often?</p>

<p>You don’t necessarily have to start changing anything right now. It’s good if you just know about these two lists.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Remember to whom and for what you are grateful</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/26/26.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Remember to whom and for what you are grateful" /><published>2024-08-26T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2024-08-26T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/26/26</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/26/26.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/mindfulmonth/assets/images/26.jpg" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<h2 id="remember-to-whom-and-for-what-you-are-grateful">Remember to whom and for what you are grateful</h2>

<p>Gratitude is a simple way to be happy.</p>

<p>Choose a time for this practice. The time of day isn’t very important, but it is important that nothing distracts you—this practice requires a few minutes of reflection. For example, it’s convenient to do this in the evening, at home. It will be even better if you do it in writing.</p>

<p>Sit down and ask yourself “Who am I grateful to?”</p>

<p>Perhaps someone close to you will come to mind, or just a stranger who was kind to you once. Or it could be a colleague who taught you something.</p>

<p>Or ask yourself “What am I grateful for?”</p>

<p>You can feel gratitude simply for something regardless of other people. For example, you can be grateful just for being alive and relatively healthy, not hungry, having a place to live, and having an interesting job. There are many reasons to experience a feeling of gratitude.</p>

<p>In difficult moments, it may seem that everything is bad and nothing is working out. This is because your focus is strongly shifted towards immediate problems. The practice of gratitude helps to dispel this illusion and see what you didn’t notice before.</p>

<p>Regular practice of gratitude can seriously change your perception of life. It’s impossible to be grateful and dissatisfied at the same time.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Talk to your loved one</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/25/25.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Talk to your loved one" /><published>2024-08-25T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2024-08-25T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/25/25</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/25/25.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/mindfulmonth/assets/images/25.jpg" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<h2 id="talk-to-your-loved-one">Talk to your loved one</h2>

<p>Today’s healthy habit is about mindfulness and relationships between people.</p>

<p>When people don’t talk much to each other about what concerns them and keep it to themselves, “baggage” accumulates. This isn’t primarily about grievances or complaints. It’s important to talk about everything that concerns each of you and what you want to discuss. But often people don’t do this.</p>

<p>Choose a time during the day, about 10 minutes, to talk with someone close to you. This could be your spouse or another close person. At the chosen time, simply start a conversation. What exactly you start talking about isn’t very important: you can just start with the question “How are you?”, or share an impression about the day, or bring up your own topic. And then - see how it goes.</p>

<p>Such a conversation is also a mindfulness exercise; during it, you need to listen and hear this person and yourself. Try to understand both of you, simultaneously.</p>

<p>Don’t create expectations for the conversation - don’t wait for any specific result. It’s like in meditation: the process is important, in this case - the conversation itself.</p>

<p>At the end, “listen” to yourself - what do you feel? What was the feeling before the conversation?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Call a friend or relative you haven’t talked to for a long time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/24/24.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Call a friend or relative you haven’t talked to for a long time" /><published>2024-08-24T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2024-08-24T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/24/24</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/24/24.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/mindfulmonth/assets/images/24.jpg" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<h2 id="call-a-friend-or-relative-you-havent-talked-to-for-a-long-time">Call a friend or relative you haven’t talked to for a long time</h2>

<p>Sometimes we don’t communicate with loved ones due to everyday reasons, like moving to another city. Sometimes because of this, the connection begins to fade.</p>

<p>Choose a close person you haven’t talked to in a long time and give them a call. Just like that, without any particular reason. Don’t create any expectations beforehand.</p>

<p>It could be an old friend or a relative. Who exactly doesn’t matter, as long as you have pleasant feelings when you think about this person.</p>

<p>Don’t start the conversation with a blame game like “Why don’t you call or write?” or “Where have you been?”. Don’t be shy to say if you’re happy to hear them and have missed them.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Leave your phone, computer, and tablet outside the bedroom</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/23/23.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leave your phone, computer, and tablet outside the bedroom" /><published>2024-08-23T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2024-08-23T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/23/23</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/23/23.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/mindfulmonth/assets/images/23.jpg" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<h2 id="leave-your-phone-computer-and-tablet-outside-the-bedroom">Leave your phone, computer, and tablet outside the bedroom</h2>

<p>Yesterday’s task was to go to bed an hour earlier, and we also shared several habits that positively affect sleep. Today, we’ll return to one of them.</p>

<p>To prevent phone and tablet use from reducing sleep quality, don’t bring them into the bedroom. And don’t bring your laptop either. It’s not just about melatonin production—an extra dose of information doesn’t help you sleep better either. When you mindlessly scroll through social media or read news before bed, you continue thinking about something, while you should be relaxing and going to sleep.</p>

<p>The start of your day will also be better—after waking up, you won’t be able to check notifications immediately. Instead, you can slowly come to your senses, have a “clear” head for at least a few minutes. Stretch, listen to your body, set your mood for the day—give yourself some time. This is the time for yourself that you might have been missing.</p>

<p>If your devices charge in the bedroom, move the chargers to another room and leave the devices there overnight.</p>

<p>If you wake up to an alarm on your phone, this time set the alarm louder, and then—buy a separate alarm clock.</p>

<p>If you want, you can develop this practice and not touch your devices until you leave the house. You’ll learn about all emails once you’re at work, and you’ll spend your morning here and now.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Go to bed an hour earlier</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/22/22.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Go to bed an hour earlier" /><published>2024-08-22T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2024-08-22T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/22/22</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/22/22.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/mindfulmonth/assets/images/22.jpg" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<h2 id="go-to-bed-an-hour-earlier">Go to bed an hour earlier</h2>

<p>Sleep greatly affects how we feel. To feel good, we need to get enough sleep.</p>

<p>Set a goal for today — go to bed an hour earlier. To make it happen, allocate time for your evening routine — half an hour or an hour — and set a reminder for this time so you can start preparing for bed on time.</p>

<p>Perhaps you’ve been dreaming of getting enough sleep for a long time, and every morning is difficult for you. Today is the day when you can fulfill the promise you made to yourself.</p>

<p>To improve your sleep, try these techniques:</p>

<h3 id="dont-use-your-phone-or-tablet-for-an-hour-before-bed">Don’t use your phone or tablet for an hour before bed</h3>

<p>Light, especially bright and cold, interferes with the body’s production of melatonin — the sleep hormone. Because of this, it’s harder for you to fall asleep, and your sleep is less deep and restorative than it could be.</p>

<p>If you regularly work on a computer before bed, install the F.lux program — it will adjust the screen’s light temperature according to the time of day. This feature is already built into macOS and iOS.</p>

<h3 id="air-out-and-cool-down-the-room-and-bed">Air out and cool down the room and bed</h3>

<p>Sleep is much better if the room temperature is slightly lower than what we’re used to. This is why it’s harder to fall asleep in the heat of summer. Just be careful not to overdo it and catch a cold.</p>

<h3 id="dont-drink-coffee-black-or-green-tea">Don’t drink coffee, black or green tea</h3>

<p>If you drink coffee, have your last cup by 4:00 PM at the latest, ideally no later than 2:00 PM. In the evening, it’s better not to drink regular tea either; opt for chamomile tea instead.</p>

<h3 id="relax">Relax</h3>

<p>When you lie down, listen to your body, check if there’s any tension. Mentally go through your muscles and try to relax them. Then take a deep breath, hold it for a second, and as you exhale, try to relax the muscles in your chest, abdomen, and back.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Take a walk</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/21/21.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Take a walk" /><published>2024-08-21T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2024-08-21T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/21/21</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mindfulmonth/2024/08/21/21.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/mindfulmonth/assets/images/21.jpg" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<h2 id="take-a-walk">Take a walk</h2>

<p>Go for a walk just because.</p>

<p>Not on your way to the store, but just go out for a walk. Not for 15 or 30 or 60 minutes, but for as long as you want.</p>

<p>Choose and set aside time for this.</p>

<p>At the appointed hour — get up and go.</p>

<p>During the walk, you don’t need to do anything special. If you want to be here and now and spend this time mindfully — be. If you want to think about a task that has been on your mind for a while — think. The main thing is to take a walk and be with yourself.</p>

<p>And yes, dress for the weather.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>